<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James Thomas</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on James Thomas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Downloading files from the CMA website in an automated way using R</title>
      <link>/2021/05/03/downloading-files-from-the-cma-website-in-an-automated-way-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/05/03/downloading-files-from-the-cma-website-in-an-automated-way-using-r/</guid>
      <description>div.blue { border: 0.1em solid #e0dff3; background-color:#f0f4f9; padding-left: 1.5em; padding-right: 1em; padding-top: 0.25em; padding-bottom: 0.5em}This post is slightly specific to my work. The Competition and Markets Authority (“CMA”) will often publish documents at various points during its cases. I was prompted to write this short piece of code to automate the downloading of these documents when the CMA published 80+ responses from stakeholders to a particular set of working papers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating drive times in Stata using the osrmtime command</title>
      <link>/2021/03/14/calculating-drive-times-in-stata-using-the-osrmtime-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/03/14/calculating-drive-times-in-stata-using-the-osrmtime-command/</guid>
      <description>This post walks through the (somewhat fiddly) installation and usage of the osrmtime command. It is a Stata command for calculating distances and travel times between two sets of GPS coordinates on a map.
This is done using:
OpenStreetMaps for your map (which you are required to download before running the command such that everything works totally offline)the Open Source Routing Machine (“OSRM”) to determine the shortest distance between A and BIf you have the time to spare, I would read the osrmtime author guide (it’s only 7 pages), but if not, this post is self-contained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>13/05/2021 I am currently working in NERA Economic Consulting&amp;rsquo;s Antitrust and Competition Practice in London. I have worked on a variety of interesting competition cases across a range of industries and jurisdictions (see my CV for more detail).
This site is mainly a place for me to keep track of various bits I have worked on and may want to look back on at some point (or share with others when potentially helpful).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>div.blue { border: 0.1em solid #e0dff3; background-color:#f0f4f9; padding-left: 30px; padding-right: 20px; padding-top: 30px; padding-bottom: 20px}13/05/2021 Experience NERA Economic Consulting, Research Officer Oct 2019-Present, (1 year, 7 months) I am currently working in NERA&amp;rsquo;s Antitrust and Competition Practice in London. My experience includes working on a variety of market investigation, merger, cartel, abuse of dominance and state aid cases across a range of industries and jurisdictions.
During my first year at NERA, I spent a lot of time working on a market investigation before the Competition and Markets Authority (&amp;ldquo;CMA&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
